In this lesson, you'll
practice setting up rules-based evals,
which are
fast and cheap to run. So rules-based
evals are
suitable for the early, iterative stage of
development, in which you'll
run these tests
frequently, anytime you add a
feature or fix a bug.
Once you have your first evals set up,
you'll have a chance to see them
run in an automated continuous integration
pipeline.
Let's get started.
So we're going to start with an
overview of automated evals.
Ultimately, we want you to
come out of this
set of lessons with
a good understanding of
how to build software effectively,
how to build high-quality software, how
to be able to move
quickly and get great feedback
on everything that you're building.
And this is a thing that's
well understood in more
traditional forms of software, but
is shifting as many of
us start to build LLM-powered applications.
. If
we compare traditional
software to LLM-based applications,
we can see a few
fundamental differences.
Overall, from a behavior perspective,
traditional software tends
to be focused around things that
are predefined.
We know what the inputs are,
and we know as a
result of any particular input
what the output will be.
And that's
fairly straightforward to test for.
By contrast,
in LLM based applications,
we know what the inputs are,
but we get a set of possible outputs.
So it's
more probabilistic in nature.
Many of these applications
are based on natural language.
This could be highly subjective.
and if your application
does things like summarizing,
then it's
quite possible that there will
be many good outcomes. Outcomes
that are good enough and would
be considered correct, there
are also many incorrect
possible outcomes or outputs.
And so the approach to
testing can be quite different.
For example, if you were to prompt
an LLM to answer the question,
is Italy a good place to take a
vacation?
One answer could be yes.
You can go to Rome, go to Florence,
you can go to Venice,
you can also explore museums,
you could explore beaches.
Another answer could be
a single word answer.
Yes.
Which one is considered better
will depend on your use case. It's
also important to note that LLMs
can produce harmful responses. They
might be toxic, they
might be offensive.
And so LLMs bring new challenges
to application testing
compared to traditional software.
To deal with these new testing
challenges, AI researchers developed
the concept of evaluations or evals
to assess how LLMs are doing
at specific tasks.
There are many common
data sets for different tasks.
Examples include MMLU, HeLaSwag,
and human eval. LLMs are often
tested on different data sets so
researchers have a
point of comparison between models.
However, what we're going to talk about
is building your own
application and testing for
your specific use case.
Okay, so as I mentioned, there's
some standard benchmarks, these
are some examples, but
these are not necessarily going to
give you great information about what
works the best in your specific
application and for
your use cases.
So we're going to take the
time in this lesson
to start building the
tools to evaluate when you're building
your own application.
What's great about all of
these benchmarks and the
existence of evals to
perform these benchmarks is
that we have a lot of the tooling
in place that we can use to start
testing our own applications.
And in many cases,
these evals are run manually,
which is great for
some quick feedback as you're
building, but
once you get to scale, once you're working
with other team members
and continuing to work
and move forward, you want
to have a tool that's going to
keep checking the quality
of your work and
of your application, again,
across larger team,
across time, and that's what
we're going to build to
over the course of
this set of lessons so once we have
the ability to perform
automated evals it's important
for us to understand
what we're looking for
and when we should
be performing these automated
evals in terms of
what there's four main
areas that we think about
first context adherence or
groundedness, which is the
question of whether the
LLM response aligns with the
provided context or guidelines.
Next is context relevance, and that's
the question of whether
the retrieved context is
relevant to the original
query or prompt. Next, we
have correctness or accuracy, which
is really, does the LLM output
align with the
provided ground truth and the expected
results?
How close is it to what we would
anticipate in the given scenario?
And then finally, we're
concerned with bias and toxicity, which
are really negative potential
that exist in the
world of LLM-powered apps.
First, bias should be favoritism
or prejudice towards or
away from certain groups.
And then toxicity, harmful words or
implicit wording that
is offensive to certain groups.
And then in terms of when,
in a traditional software model, we're
typically testing after every change, whether
that's bug fixes, feature updates,
or even
data changes or changes
to the model, which might
be a different case
when you're evaluating from
an LOM perspective.
If that becomes slow or takes
too long you can also start
to pull out
more comprehensive testing
to specific points like pre-deployment.
So doing more comprehensive testing
at the point that you're looking at pushing
something into a
production environment or
post deployment because some of these
changes might occur once your software
is actually executing in a production
environment, which
is again a bit of a shift from
our traditional software models.
Okay, so let's get started putting all
of this into practice.
In order to
start understanding this framework,
we're going to build an AI-powered quiz
generator. The app
will have a dataset
comprised of facts categorized
across art, science, and
geography.
The facts are grouped into specific
subjects.
Some of those subjects
apply to multiple categories.
For example, Paris is home to
many great works of
art and scientific inventions.
The user will ask our
bot to write a quiz
about a given topic and
get back a set of questions.
We'll write evaluations to check
that the bot is
using the appropriate facts
and only using facts
from our data set.
So let's jump in.
In order to get things going,
we have to do a little bit of setup.
This application and
executing the application
for automated evals requires us to
use a couple of third party
services, including CircleCI,
GitHub, and OpenAI. So we're
going to put some keys
in place to give us
access to those things and
set up our GitHub repo.
This is all done for you,
we just need to put the code in place.
So for the purposes of
the lesson and this entire course,
there are some utility
functions to make these
things easier and we'll
use those as you'll see
here from this utils
package to put our
keys in place and get our environment set
up in order to
to execute our application.
Now we have those three
keys in place for the
three external services that we're
going to use to make this work CircleCI,
GitHub and OpenAI.
The work to do that, as noted,
is in the utils package,
and these keys have been provided.
If you want to take this
and do something bigger over time,
then you would need to
go sign up for those services,
but they're provided for the purpose
of this lesson. And now, as
you can see, we have our GitHub repo
and branch in place.
There's a generated branch for each
student so that it doesn't conflict
with everyone else's work.
And again, that's done for you so
that you can get
through that lesson very easily.
We're going to start by
using the evals locally, but
as the point of this is
to get to automated evals, we
will use GitHub and
CircleCI to push the
code into GitHub and
then have that push
code into CircleCI for
the purpose of executing
the automated eval, which
again gets us to
that place where as we grow our team,
as we work over time, we don't have
to worry about whether
everything has been tested
because it all gets
tested on our behalf
each time we make
a change, helping us
to move confidently and quickly
as we build.
Okay, so now let's get into creating
the actual application.
As described, we're
going to build a quiz
generator powered by AI.
We have a few different subjects,
and first we're
going to build the template.
Now note that we're
going to store a lot of our
data in strings so that it's visible
on the screen and in our templates. If
this were larger or if
you were building this as a real application,
you'd be much
more likely to put this data into files
or into a database
so that you could
build it more dynamically.
This is really built this
way to help you see
it very clearly and make
it easier to work with.
So the first thing that we've
built here is the data
set for the quiz.
And the goal is to have the quiz
generator, based on the LLM,
specifically choose questions
and answers from this data set
and not to choose questions and
answers from anywhere else. So we're
going to work with
the validity of that
as we start to build out the application.
So this is our
underlying data set that we're
going to use.
And now we're going to build
a prompt template that will allow
us to ask for specific quizzes
and validate that
those quizzes are
actually generated based
on this data that we've provided.
So take a moment
to read the content
of this prompt template,
because this is what's
ultimately submitted to the
LLM based on information
provided in the request, in
addition to the content that you
saw in the quiz bank, which
will be injected into here.
So I think it's really valuable to
understand how this template is structured.
This is how we're going to get the
request constructed or the
prompt to the LLM.
And so you can see it's
written here in fairly plain English
with some specific
instructions for the LLM.
And if you look at
where the QuizBank placeholder is,
that will include the
data that we just
created as our data
set and then combine
it with these instructions,
which basically ask for the LLM
to generate a quiz customized in
specific steps.
So first, based on the category
the user is asking about,
as discussed, we have three options
that are available within
our quiz for categories, geography,
science, and art. We've
explicitly outlined those.
And then the second step is
to identify the subject that we're
going to generate the questions about,
and those are pulled from
the quiz bank.
Choose up to two of those,
and then in step three,
generate a quiz based
on those two choices,
the category and the subjects,
and then use a specific
format to generate the quiz,
which we'll
see once we start running it. Now
we're going
to take advantage of a third-party toolkit, Langchain,
in order to
build a prompt template
that we can use
to submit all of the pieces that we
just outlined to an
LLM.
So if you print this out,
you can see the
content or the generated object,
which is the chat prompt that we're
now going to use to
submit to the LLM.
So next, let's choose an LLM.
Now, we'll also use Langchain to
get ourselves access to
an LLM for the rest of our actions
here. We're choosing
to use OpenAI's GPT-35 Turbo.
You have the option
to choose many different LLMs,
both depending on
your personal choices,
as well as the
option to choose different
ones to try to
get different results if you're
not getting the right output for
your particular use case. And
now we need a parser that's going
to take the response
from the LLM and
give us something useful. And in
our case, we just
want a string.
So we're using Langchain's str
output parser. And now we're going to
connect all these pieces together using
the pipe operator
from the Langchain
expression language.
You can think of this
as taking the output of
one and piping it into
the input of the next,
the whole thing think of as a pipeline.
So we're taking the chat prompt, piping
it to the LLM, and
then piping the response
through the output parser
to get our string. Now
to take each of
those components and make
it reusable as one piece, we're going
to build that into a
function that we're calling assistant
chain in order to
be able to continue to use this.
Now that we've
seen how each of those pieces works, we're
going to package that up into
our quiz assistant, which is
built on that chain, so that
we can use it repeatedly as we test
and evaluate different responses.
So now
that we have all the pieces, we're going
to start actually building
the evaluations for
our assistant. In this first
case, we're going to be
looking for expected words,
meaning when we ask
the assistant to generate
a quiz for us,
there will be specific
words that we would
expect to see in
the response.
So for our first example, we're
going to generate a fairly straightforward
quiz about science, and
then we have this
list of expected words
that we assume if the quiz is generated
correctly based on the
dataset that we provided, then
some of these words will appear. This
is a fairly straightforward rules-based eval
meaning we are using known inputs
for our testing.
In a later lesson we will look at
model graded evals where
we actually use the
power of the LLM
not just to generate
the quiz but also
to evaluate the quality
of the quiz after it's
been generated.
So now that we have all these pieces we've
created our eval which is
looking for expected words.
We have the question we want to ask.
We have the expected words that we're
looking for.
We can execute all of this
as an eval and see what happens.
Okay as you can see now we're
talking to a real LLM and this takes
a little bit of time as we make
the request and get
back the response.
But here you can see what's
generated for us, which
is a quiz about science.
And it contains at least some
of the words that we expected.
So it's going to pass our eval. Because
of the way that we
created this particular eval, the
eval. Because the way that we
eval expected words function, we
used an assert to throw
an exception in the case
where the eval fails.
But because our expected words were
found in this particular quiz,
it passed and printed out the
answer without any extra output.
So now let's
move on and create a failing eval.
So in this case, what we're
going to do is ask
the application to answer a
question that it doesn't have
any information about. And what
we want to happen is that the assistant
will decline to answer
rather than making up
its own questions.
However, we haven't
actually created those restrictions
in our prompt.
So we're going to run this, and
what we should see is
a failure of our eval.
So as you can see in this case, we're
going to ask for a
quiz specifically about Rome.
And again, we're
hoping for the assistant to
decline in a polite and
apologetic way by saying, I'm sorry.
And so let's run that
and see what happens.
Again, you see some time as
we connect to the LLM,
submit our prompt and
get back the response.
But what we got back from
a response was an actual quiz,
which we did not expect.
And so in this case,
you can see what
happens with the assertion,
which is that an error
is thrown indicating that I'm
sorry was not contained in
any of this text. Again, you
can see an actual quiz
that was returned to us. And
as you can see right here, we
expected the bot to decline with I'm sorry
and instead got the full
text of the quiz, which does
not contain in it
anywhere the text, I'm sorry.
This would be a great place to stop
the video for a
minute and explore this
eval to ensure that
you really understand what's
happening.
Because we passed expected
words that we know will be in the
response,
nothing happened other than
printing out the response.
Only something interesting will
happen if the eval fails,
which in this case
would mean finding none
of the expected words.
So take the opportunity
to play with the
expected words and see
what happens when they aren't
found in the response
from the assistant.
And what you should see
is that an exception is
thrown based on the assert.
Later in the lesson we're
going to use a similar
prompt for the quiz assistant,
but modify it so that
it would pass this
test in that it will refuse to create
quizzes based on data
that it doesn't already
have stored in its dataset. So from
these examples, you can see that running
evaluations on your
LLM apps can be extremely helpful
in assessing your
LLMs performance, in discovering
areas for improvement, and enhancing
the overall functionality
and reliability of
your LLM-based applications.
But you can also
imagine that if you
had to run those
evaluations manually for every
change, the process would
become tedious and time-consuming.
Now multiply those
inefficiencies across a team, 10,
20, 100 contributors. It's
just not scalable.
So instead, now let's look at how we
would set up these evals to run automatically
in a continuous integration
process. In this case, we'll
be using CircleCI, and ultimately,
this will
allow your team to
stay focused on developing
new features. For our
first round of evals, we'll focus on
adding basic checks similar to the
ones that we've used so far
to ensure that our assistant is being set
up properly and producing
valid results.
These are the kinds of checks that you'll
probably run every time
you make a change
to your application.
In later lessons, we'll
look at more advanced checks, including
model-graded evals
that we might want
to run on a
different cadence. Your CI-CD pipeline will
automatically run these
different types of
evals depending on
the situation that
you're in. And if any one
of these automated checks
fails, your pipeline will stop
running and notify you what went
wrong so that you can fix
the problem and get back to
innovating. For this notebook, we're
using the GitHub API
to commit code.
In your normal workflow, it's
more likely that you would
use the Git command or
command line tools like GH.
As a reminder, any code you push
to GitHub will be
publicly visible because we've
set up the course to let
you practice these
exercises without logging
into your own
GitHub account.
For your own projects, you'll
want to use your own GitHub account, and
you can use a
private repository if that's what
you need.
As mentioned previously, we've
updated the application
prompt to decline
generating quizzes for
topics for which there is no
information. In other words, we
want the LLM to rely
on the available context and
not on information that it
may have from pre-training to
limit the possibility
of hallucination.
Now we're taking the content of
much of what we've built
already and putting it into
a single app.py file on
the file system.
In order to see the contents,
you can use the cat command to dump
that content back out
into your notebook environment.
However, you'll note that the syntax
highlighting is not visible, which
makes it a little bit
more difficult to read.
As a reminder,
this is the code that we've
already stepped through. We
are just taking it and consolidating
it into a single file so
that we can put it into Git and ultimately
into our continuous
integration platform.
I'd like to draw your
attention to two specific
points in this revised
prompt.
The first is this line with
an explicit instruction
to only reference facts in the
included list of topics.
The second further down is specific
instructions on what to do in
the case that there is no
information about the
subject that the user is asking
about and providing
specific text to say, I'm sorry, but
I do not have
information on that topic.
Now we've created a separate file, testassistant.py,
which we're using as
the structure of our
evals and the specific
test cases.
This is similar to what we
did previously in
terms of evaluating
for expected words
and evaluating for refusal, and we're
reusing these in a
couple different test cases
which I will show
you again we can use cat to see
the contents of this
file in this case we're looking
at testassistant.py which includes
the functions that
we defined previously
for evaluating expected
words and evaluating
refusal and then
structuring those into
specific test cases
which I'll walk you through
now the first test
case is similar to
what we did previously
around a science quiz.
So we ask the LLM or the assistant
to generate a quiz
about science, and then we look
for specifically the expected
subjects that we know
should come from our
dataset.
Next, we take a similar approach and
generate a quiz about geography.
We use the same function,
eval expected words,
but this time we
pass in a different
set of subjects that
we would expect to be present in a
quiz about geography. And finally,
we redo the test refusal,
in this case asking
the assistant to generate
a quiz about Rome
and expecting the response
to include the words I'm sorry. But
I'd like to draw your attention
specifically to the system
message which we've modified in
order to get the
correct behavior.
As we saw previously when we
asked for a quiz about Rome,
despite it not being one of
the explicitly identified
categories, we got a quiz.
And so we've added these two additional
rules at the bottom.
First, only use explicit
matches for the category.
If the category is not an exact match,
answer that you do
not have the information.
And second, if the user asks a
question about a subject you
do not have information about,
answer with this specific text, I'm
sorry, I
do not have information about, answer
with this specific text, I'm sorry,
I do
not have information about that.
So some very explicit
instructions given as part
of the prompt to ensure that if the
data is not available, we don't
get made up quizzes about
things that are not understood
in our data set.
Okay,
so we have all the pieces in place.
In order to run these evals
in our continuous
integration environment,
which in this case is CircleCI.
We do have a CircleCI configuration
file contained in the lab.
You don't need to know anything
about that right now.
We'll talk about some of the details
of that in a later lesson. So
now we're going to push the two files
that we created to our
repo on our branch, which means
we're pushing them
to GitHub.
Again, we're
using a utility function that we've written
to make this easier for the
purposes of the lab, so we
can see the outcome. And now
we're going to trigger a pipeline on
CircleCI, and you can
see the URL is passed back to us
of where we can find that pipeline. So
here we see the execution
of our evals in the automated
environment on CircleCI.
A number of steps
here are based around
setting up the environment,
creating the appropriate
Python or installing
the appropriate Python version,
installing the dependencies,
and then ultimately running our evals,
which happens right here.
And you can see that we used PyTest
to run the testassistant.py
that we looked at earlier, and
all of our tests passed
in just under 12 seconds.
And this is something
that will happen every
time we make a
change to ensure that we haven't
broken anything in perhaps
edits that we make
to our prompt or edits that we make
to our application.
Excellent. So in this lesson,
you wrote some very
simple string matching evals
and learned how to run them in a
CI pipeline.
In the next lesson, you'll
learn how to use LLMs to do model-graded evals
and introduce those into
your pipeline.
See you in the next lesson.